<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Terminal</title>
    <link>/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 16:15:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 16:15:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>It Begins A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step, and this site is mine. I’m Glenn Lewis, and I have been working in tech for 10 years. During that time, I’ve become adept at Linux administration, Python scripting, Incident Management, and System Observability. Like most people who haven’t gone through a typical education path, my knowledge had been built through hands-on experience and tribal knowledge.
What I would like to do with this site is track my continuing journey in software development and share my experience.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-begins&#34;&gt;It Begins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step, and this site is mine. I’m Glenn Lewis, and I have been working in tech for 10 years. During that time, I’ve become adept at Linux administration, Python scripting, Incident Management, and System Observability. Like most people who haven’t gone through a typical education path, my knowledge had been built through hands-on experience and tribal knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I would like to do with this site is track my continuing journey in software development and share my experience. I hope to share resources, pitfalls, and advice that others might find useful. Ellen Ulman once said “Programmers seem to be changing the world. It would be a relief, for them and for all of us, if they knew something about it,” and that is what I intend to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
